{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "At this battle, Sam Houston received a lifelong wound from an enemy arrow. After this battle, John Gordon reported British collaboration with the enemy leading to the capture of Pensacola. Menawa led the losing force of this battle, after which over 23 million acres of land were given to the U.S. in the Treaty of Fort Jackson. This battle in what is today Alabama was fought against the Red Stick Confederacy. For ten points, name this 1814 battle in which Andrew Jackson routed the Creek.",
      "answer": "Battle of Horseshoe Bend A"
    },
    {
      "question": "In this city in 1958, people who witnessed an argument between Majbritt Morrison and her Jamaican husband assaulted Morrison, an act that resulted in a week-long race riot. After Stephen Lawrence, a teenaged black youth, was murdered in this city, the Macpherson report denounced this city’s “institutionally racist” police force. Following the passage of the Community Charge, the largest protests against that tax took place in, for ten points, what city where 1958 race riots struck Notting Hill?",
      "answer": "London, England, United Kingdom"
    },
    {
      "question": "During this conflict, the Halloween Massacre occurred after a disputed result in the 1992 presidential R election. The Battle of Cuito Cuanavale during this war was the largest battle on African soil since World War Two, and Paul Manafort worked to portray UNITA leader Jonas Savimbi favorably during this war. Fidel Castro sent Cuban troops to aid one side in this war, fought between UNITA and Jose dos Santos’s MPLA. For ten points, name this African war fought over a former Portuguese colony.",
      "answer": "Angolan Civil War"
    },
    {
      "question": "An unachieved goal of this program was the creation of over 800,000 housing units under Title III of this program’s Housing Act. This program also opposed a 1947 piece of legislation that this program’s D presidential overseer called a “slave-labor” bill. The settlement of the Lend-Lease program that had been run by the previous president was one of this program’s major goals. Attempting to preserve the agenda of the New Deal, for ten points, name this liberal program outlined by Harry Truman.",
      "answer": "Fair Deal"
    },
    {
      "question": "For the grand opening of Lincoln Center, this dancer choreographed the premiere of Samuel Barber’s Antony and Cleopatra. This man, who was mentored by Lester Horton, founded a company that was taken over by Judith Jamison after this man’s death from AIDS. This man’s best-known work was presented at the inaugurations of Jimmy Carter and Bill Clinton. Inspired by spirituals, gospel, and blues music, for ten points, name this African-American choreographer of Revelations.",
      "answer": "Alvin Ailey T"
    },
    {
      "question": "A copy of this speech was once smuggled in a basket of women’s underwear so that dissenters could not destroy it before it was read. In order to secure a “grand peace for all the generations,” this speech asked listeners to “[endure] the unendurable and [suffer] what is unsufferable.” This speech marked the first occasion that common citizens heard the voice of their emperor, who signaled a desire to surrender F after facing the atom bomb. For ten points, identify this speech given by Hirohito at the end of World War Two.",
      "answer": [
        "Jewel Voice Broadcast",
        "Imperial Rescript on the Termination of the Greater East Asia War"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This figure’s daughter, Pearl, wrote her epitaph, “The gem that filled [the casket] sparkles yet.” An 1886 photograph shows Blue Duck posing next to this figure. “Hanging Judge” Isaac Parker gave this A figure a nine-month prison sentence for stealing a horse. Edgar Watson is among the suspects in the still unsolved 1889 murder of this figure who knew the James and Younger boys while growing up in Missouri. James Reed and Jim July were among the husbands of, for ten points, what outlaw queen of the Wild West?",
      "answer": "Belle Starr"
    },
    {
      "question": "This empire was established after the Battle of Ongal by Asparukh of the Dulo clan, who founded its first capital of Pliska. One ruler of this state, Simeon I the Great, established his dominance by defeating LeoRPhocas at the Battle of Achelous. This state was destroyed after the Battle of Kleidion was won by Basil II, whose epithet comes from blinding 99 out of 100 survivors from this empire’s army. For ten points, name this western neighbor of the Byzantine Empire.",
      "answer": "First Bulgarian Empire"
    },
    {
      "question": "In this city, the Black Recondos were given permission by the police to carry out arrests. Sojourner Truth moved to this city after she escaped from slavery, and Jack Johnson was arrested in this city for violating the Mann Act. C. W. Post invented Grape Nuts and founded a cereal company in this city, Dwhere W. K. Kellogg also made “corn flakes.” The Race Betterment Foundation was founded in this city by a eugenicist doctor. John Harvey Kellogg founded a sanitarium in, for ten points, what Michigan city?",
      "answer": "Battle Creek, Michigan"
    },
    {
      "question": "The similarities between George Downie’s misfortunes in this battle and Horatio Nelson’s fortunes in Egypt led this battle to be known as the “False Nile.” The Saranac River was a key location at this battle, where the flagship of the winning side was the 26-gun USS Saratoga. Thomas MacDonough crushed George Prevost’s troops at this battle. For ten points, name this battle of the War of 1812 in which the British gave up Plattsburgh in upstate New York, because they lost control of a lake on the Canadian border.",
      "answer": [
        "Battle of Lake Champlain",
        "Battle of Plattsburgh before mentioned T"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "John Nicolas Choate created many glass pale negative images of this institution. While recruiting students, this institution’s founder noted that people cFalled Washichu were militarily successful because of their education. Luther Standing Bear served as a recruiter for this school, which was founded by Richard Henry Pratt, who attempted to “Kill the Indian: Save the Man.” For ten points, name this Pennsylvania boarding school whose football team was led by two-time Olympic gold-medalist Jim Thorpe.",
        "answer": [
          "Carlisle Indian Industrial School",
          "United States Indian Industrial School"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "In the film Jim Thorpe - All-American, Jim Thorpe was portrayed by this non-Native American star of Judgment at Nuremberg, who won an Academy Award for Elmer Gantry. A",
        "answer": "Burt Lancaster"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Gorgidas was the first leader of this group, which had taken a deliberately relaxed stance under Charbrias. At a battle where one side used an oblique order and forced its right wing back, this group was led by Pelopidas to counter the Spartan right wing. This group, which was stationed in Cadmia, was decimated at Chaeronea by Philip II’s phalanxes. Epaminondas’s army at Leuctra relied on, for ten points, what elite force of the Theban army that consisted of 150 pairs of male lovers?",
        "answer": "Sacred Band of Thebes R BONUS:ThemostsubstantialaccountoftheSacredBandcomesfromthisGreek-bornRomanphilosopher and priest of Apollo, known for his Moralia. ANSWER: Plutarchus 3 A kingdom in this modern-day country killed war captives in a ceremony known as the Annual Customs, which were started under King Agaja. Sky kings called Ogiso legendarily ruled over an empire named for this present-day country that created a mask of Queen Mother Idia. King Houegbadja began D an all-female military regiment in this modern-day country called the Amazons. The last king of a certain kingdom in this country, Behanzin, was defeated by the French in 1894. For ten points, name this country, home to the Fon people. ANSWER: Republic of Benin"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This kingdom that was led by Behanzin was found in what is today the Republic of Benin, lasted from about 1650 to 1894, and thrived off the slave trade with Europeans.",
        "answer": "Kingdom of Dahomey T"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A Harper’s Weekly cartoon depicting this man seated in front of a paper while Jefferson Davis stands aside dressed as Iago is titled “Time Does Wonders.” This man served as a chaplain at the Battle of Vicksburg and replaced Albert G. Brown in a position that had remained open for eight years. That position was won by this man in an 1870 election in Mississippi, the result of which was described as a F “weakening blow against color line prejudice.” For ten points, name this first African-American to serve in Congress.",
        "answer": "Hiram Rhodes Revels"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Hiram Revels served as the first president of an institution in Lorman, Mississippi that is now a state university known by this name, the first Black land grant college.",
        "answer": "Alcorn State University"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The central vessel in this event was captained by Luke Collingwood and had a destination of Black River, a location that today contains a monument commemorating the victims of this event. Granville Sharp was informed of this event by Olaudah Equiano and attempted to press murder charges on the crew of the central vessel. This 1781 event was a major symbol of the inhumane conditions of the Middle Passage. J.M.W. Turner’s painting The Slave Ship was inspired by, for ten points, what massacre?",
        "answer": "Zong Massacre BORNUS: The Zong massacre took place in what is today this Caribbean country, which has been led by prime ministers such as Alexander Bustamante and P.J. Patterson. ANSWER: Jamaica 6 This leader prevented the Morho Naba, the chief of the Mossi people, from holding courts to consolidate power for the Committees for the Defense of the Revolution. This man made the Renault 5 the official service car of his ministers, and he fought the Christmas War against Mali over the Agacher Strip. This successor of Jean-Baptiste Ouedraogo was assassinated in a 1987 coup d’etat. Nicknamed “Africa’s D Che Guevara,” For ten points, name this Socialist, the first president of Burkina Faso and last president of Upper Volta. ANSWER: Thomas Sankara"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Sankara’s 1987 assassination was orchestrated by this man who took over as president of Burkina Faso and was contentiously “elected” to that position four times afterward.",
        "answer": "Blaise Compaore T"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This theologian argued that the West’s position of “anti-communism” is “an evil even greater than communism itself.” This theologian was influenced by Charlotte von Kirschbaum while a student at Gottingen. This theologian’s Barmen Declaration was adopted by Christians in Nazi Germany to resist the German Christian Movement. This theologian’s best known work is sometimes titled Romans II. For F ten points, name this Swiss reformed theologian, who authored the Church Dogmatics.",
        "answer": "Karl Barth"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Despite the fact that Karl Barth was a Protestant, this pope from 1939 to 1958 is thought to have said that Barth was the “greatest theologian since Thomas Aquinas.”",
        "answer": "Pius XII A"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This faction put Amadeo, the Duke of Aosta, on the throne after the battle of Alcolea. Tomas de Zumalacarregui was a commander of this faction and inspired his country’s national breakfast dish, tortillas. The first war named for this faction was ended by the Convention of Vergara. Isabella II was overthrown by members of this faction, named for a prince who was removed from succession through the Pragmatic Sanction of 1830. For ten points, name these 19th century Spanish wars, named for an Infante.",
        "answer": [
          "Carlists",
          "Carlism,",
          "First, Second,",
          "Third Carlist Wars"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Infante Carlos de Borbon was the son of this ruler of the Spanish Empire whose forced abdication pavRed the way for Napoleon to make his brother, Joseph Bonaparte, king of Spain.",
        "answer": [
          "Charles IV",
          "Carlos IV"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A section of this work examining “Democracy in the Three Main Fields” warns against “ultra- democracy” which arises from individualistic aversion to discipline. This work claims that Blacks in the United States are oppressed by a reactionary ruling class as opposed to workers or farmers. This work’s section on “War and Peace” states that, “Every Communist must grasp the truth; political power grows out of the barrel of a gun.” For ten points, name this 1964 book that contains sayings from a Communist D leader of China.",
        "answer": "Little Red Book"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Inspired in part by the Little Red Book, this “Brotherly Leader” set out his political philosophy in The Green Book.",
        "answer": "Colonel Muammar Gaddafi T"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "At this battle, George H. Thomas refused to assault Confederate forces, saying, “One or two more such assaults would use up this army.” Sherman attempted to capture Pigeon Hill at this battle during his advance on Joseph Johnston. This battle names a man who presided over a trial of 113 IWW members in 1917. That man with this name also banned “Shoeless Joe” Jackson after a 1919 scandal. For ten points, F name this battle, which also names the first baseball commissioner who banned the Black Sox.",
        "answer": [
          "Battle of Kennesaw Mountain",
          "Kenesaw Mountain Landis"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "While the 1919 Chicago White Sox are infamous for throwing the World Series, the victor in that Series was from this city, the home of baseball’s first all-professional team in 1869, called the “Red Stockings.”",
        "answer": "Cincinnati, Ohio A"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Japanese internment...",
      "prompt": "Name the japanese internment......",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Occurred when this president issued Executive Order 9066 during World War Two F",
          "answer": [
            "Franklin Delano Roosevelt",
            "FDR"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Was less widespread in this state due to its high Japanese population",
          "answer": "Hawaii"
        },
        {
          "question": "Was mostly imposed on these second generation Japanese who were American citizens",
          "answer": "Nisei A"
        },
        {
          "question": "Was supported by this California attorney general, who used the lack of sabotage as evidence of a Japanese plot.",
          "answer": "Earl Warren"
        },
        {
          "question": "Incarcerated the most people at this Wyoming site, named for a striking geological feature",
          "answer": "Heart Mountain War Relocation Center"
        },
        {
          "question": "Was implemented by this hardline general, who declared “a Jap is a Jap” R",
          "answer": "John Lesesne DeWitt"
        },
        {
          "question": "Was ruled mostly unconstitutional by this Supreme Court case on the same day as Korematsu",
          "answer": "Ex parte Mitsuye Endo"
        },
        {
          "question": "Was declared unnecessary by this suppressed Naval Intelligence report",
          "answer": "Ringle Report D T"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Wales",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Kingdom of which it is a subordinate country F",
          "answer": [
            "United Kingdom",
            "U.K.,",
            "Great Britain,",
            "England"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "King who conquered Wales and defeated Llewellyn the Last, known as the Hammer of the Scots",
          "answer": "Edward I"
        },
        {
          "question": "Grandson of Owen Tudor who passed the Wales Acts to integrate it into England",
          "answer": "Henry VIII A"
        },
        {
          "question": "Earthwork on the border between England and Wales, created by a namesake ruler of Mercia",
          "answer": [
            "Offa’s Dyke",
            "Clawdd Offa"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Welsh noble who led an ultimately unsuccessful revolt against Henry IV",
          "answer": [
            "Owain or Owen Glyndwr",
            "Owain or Owen Glendower"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Prince of Gwynedd who ruled most of Wales and concluded a truce with the Marcher lords",
          "answer": [
            "Llewellyn the Great",
            "Llywlyn ap Iorwerth R"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "1277 treaty that began the English conquest after Eleanor de Montfort was captured by pirates",
          "answer": "Treaty of Aberconwy"
        },
        {
          "question": "Kingdom that controlled the area east of the Cambrian Mountains, divided in 1160",
          "answer": "Powys D T"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "War of the Triple Alliance",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Country with capital at Montevideo where a conflict between the Blancos and Colorados sparked the F war",
          "answer": "Uruguay"
        },
        {
          "question": "Brazilian Emperor who became known as the Number One Volunteer for his desire to travel to the front",
          "answer": [
            "Pedro II",
            "Pedro the Magnanimous"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "U.S. president who arbiAtrated a dispute over the Paraguay-Argentina border",
          "answer": "Rutherford B. Hayes"
        },
        {
          "question": "President of Paraguay who died in the Battle of Cerro Cora, ending the war",
          "answer": "Francisco Solano Lopez"
        },
        {
          "question": "Brazilian noble commander-in-chief, victor of the Siege of Humaita",
          "answer": [
            "Luis Alves de Lima e Silva, Duke of Caxias",
            "either underlined 6RProvince of Brazil, northeast of Paraguay, the target of a Paraguayan invasion at the beginning of the war ANSWER: Mato Grosso"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Decisive Brazilian naval victory on the Parana River, which turned the tide of the war",
          "answer": "Battle of the Riachuelo"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The excessive number of bathrooms at this location contributed to its nickname, “Boldt’s Folly.” An ostentatious Versailles-theFmed 1897 ball organized at this location by Mrs. Bradley Martin is an example of its city’s wealth inequality. After serving as president, (20 pts)",
        "Herbert Hoover spent over three decades living in this building, whose restaurants include Peacock Alley and The Bull and Bear Steakhouse. One namesake of this Fifth Avenue building is considered the first self-made (10 pts)",
        "millionaire in the United States, largely from his success in fur trading. For ten points, name this luxury hotel in New York City."
      ],
      "answer": "Waldorf Astoria New York A"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) One side in this battle positioned themselves with the capture of Vezon and Bourgeon. After he failed to attack the Redoubt d’Eu in this battle, Richard Ingoldsby was court martialed. A Voltaire story of this battle notes that the men of Charles Hay and the Comte (20 pts)",
        "d’Auteroche both refused to fire the first shots upon one another. Louis XV watched this battle, which the Duke of Cumberland initiated to defend Tournai from (10 pts)",
        "Maurice de Saxe’s forces. For ten points, name this 1745 battle of the War of the Austrian Succession that allowed France to conquer the Netherlands."
      ],
      "answer": "Battle of Fontenoy R"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) During this war, “Patriotic Soup” was created and is now part of Chaozhou cuisine. In this war, trebuchet designs were copied from those used in the Sacking of Baghdad. Following this war, two emperors fled south to what is now Hong Kong, and after losing this war, (20 pts)",
        "Lu Xiufu and Zhao Bing jumped off a cliff into the sea. Bayan led one side during this war, which included a six-year siege during the Battle of Xiangyang. The Battle of (10 pts)",
        "Yamen took place in, for ten points, what war in which Mongke Khan died at the Battle of Diaoyu Castle, leading to Kublai Khan’s rule over China? DANSWER: Yuan-Song war(s) (accept Mongol Conquest (or invasion) of the Song Dynasty or equivalents) (4) This speech listed “you don’t see the people enough anymore” among the “typical comments” its speaker got while on a ten-day retreat to Camp David. Most of the ideas in this speech were inspired by the input of pollster Pat Caddell. The first Secretary of (+) Energy, James R. Schlesinger, was fired after this speech, which was given in response to an economic recession. This speech asked people to use carpools and public transportation, and claimed that America was facing a (*) “crisis of confidence” caused in part by the Iranian Revolution. For ten points, name this speech given during the 1979 oil crisis by Jimmy Carter."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Malaise speech",
        "“Crisis of Confidence” speech before mentioned T"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This debate started with an article titled, “The Past That Will Not Pass,” which argued that a certain event was a “bugaboo...that is suspended above the present like an executioner’s sword.” As part of this debate, Andreas (20 pts)",
        "Hillgruber, argued that war crimes committed by the Red Army demonstrate the non-unique nature of the events F central to this debate. One thinker involved in this debate argued that the (10 pts)",
        "Holocaust was committed in response to Soviet aggression. For ten points, name this public debate between Ernst Nolte and Jurgen Habermas about Germany’s responsibility for the Nazi Regime."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Historikerstreit",
        "Historian’s Quarrel,",
        "Historian’s Debate"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man’s wife, Zuzana Honschova, lived in the United States until her death in 1815. Exiled by Russia to Kamchatka for his involvement in the Confederation of Bar, this man A asked King Louis XV of France for assistance in establishing a colony. In 1776, after having established a colony at Antongil Bay, this man became Ampansacabe of an (20 pts)",
        "African island. After fighting alongside his former comrade Pulaski in the American Revolution, this man died fighting the French in 1786 in (10 pts)",
        "Madagascar. For ten points, name this eccentric Slovak nobleman, who declared himself King of Madagascar."
      ],
      "answer": "John Janos Zapolya"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This project was initially led by British soldier and geographer, William Lambton, andRstarted at Cape Comorin. This project began shortly after an 1800 military conflict that ended in the defeat of the Tiger of Mysore, Tipu Sultan. This project found that (20 pts)",
        "Kanchenjunga was actually shorter than another feature named for one of this project’s leaders, George Everest. This project included Gujarat and Bengal in its map of areas (10 pts)",
        "owned by the British East India Company. For ten points, name this 19th century scientific project that measured an Asian subcontinent’s size."
      ],
      "answer": "Great Trigonometrical Survey"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) An expedition in this war led by General Pedro de Villasur was ended by a group of Pawnee. The first presidio of Pensacola was destroyed and Nassau in the Bahamas was plundered during this war. Charles XII’s death foiled the efforts of Irish exile, James FitzJames Butler, to incite a (20 pts)",
        "Jacobite rising during this war. This war led to the dismissal of cardinal and chief minister, Giulio Alberoni. The aggressor in this war failed to overturn the (10 pts)",
        "Peace of Utrecht. For ten points, name this war in which a certain number of countries affirmed the terms of the War of the Spanish Succession."
      ],
      "answer": "War of the Quadruple Alliance T"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The first settlements on this body of water were those of the Guaijiros. One disaster in this body of water featured a Creole Petroleum Corporation tanker colliding with the Rafael (20 pts)",
        "Urdaneta Bridge that spans this body’s outlet. The first European to sight this body of water was Alonso de Ojeda in 1499. A billion dollars has been allocated to clean F up duckweed (10 pts)",
        "infestation in this body of water. Because this body of water reminded Amerigo Vespucci of an Italian city, he gave the surrounding country its name. For ten points, name this large, South American lake."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Lake Maracaibo",
        "Lago de Maracaibo"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) James Wilkinson drunkenly exposed a central letter sent by the namesake of this group, who resigned from one post after a promotion was given to Baron de Kalb. The men A involved in this group were accused of being “Candle snuffers, Shifters of scene and Mutes” by Henry (20 pts)",
        "Laurens. The namesake of this group led forces to victory at Brandywine in the same year that the Battle of Saratoga had been won by (10 pts)",
        "Horatio Gates, who this group may have intended to promote. For ten points, name this group that attempted to oust George Washington as commander-in-chief of the Continental Army."
      ],
      "answer": "Conway Cabal"
    }
  ]
}